# AKRONG SYLVESTER SENYO KWAME

Accra, Ghana https://sylvesterakrong. vercel.app/ +233240207132

akrongsylvester@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/sylvester-akr ong-44ab4a203/ github.com/sylvesterakrong/

I am a software engineer with a passion for building magical mobile and web experiences, scaling systems up, and shipping reliable applications. I am also interested in robotics particularly aerial robotics and aerial systems.

# **Work Experience**

IT Support Technician UITS-KNUST December 2024—September 2024
Frontdesk team National Service Kumasi, Ghana

- Built a password reset email template with html,css to replace the existing template which reduced the pressure by 70% because users found it difficult to reset their student portal password.
- Troubleshooting and fixing of users issues which included software and hardware.
- Assisted users with wifi connection issues with 100% success rate.
- Installed and fixed windows related issues which resulted in a high success rate.

Software Engineer Ninja View 2024-present

Chrome Extension Team Remote

- Implemented features to enhance trade automation for users of the platform with the use of javascript and ai tools
- Redesigned the user interface to make it more appealing for users with the use of HTML, CSS and JS

Software developer Freelance 2023-Present

Accra, Ghana

Build beautiful websites for clients to improve their presence on the internet with Next JS and css tools

Software Engineer Intern ISTD-UPSA December,2022
Accra, Ghana

• Designed documentation for the admissions portal to help students understand the features of the portal to improve the user experience.

### **Education and Certifications**

- Bsc. Information Technology, Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology, Kumasi-Ghana.
   2023 to date
- Technical Support Fundamentals, Google, Cousera
   September 9,2024
- Diploma in Information Technology, Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology, Kumasi-Ghana.
   2021 to 2023
- Certificate In Software Development, The Ghana-India Kofi Annan Centre of Excellence in ICT, Accra-Ghana.
   March, 2022 to May 2022
- Certificate in Introduction to Cybercrime, SkillUP by Simplilearn.

#### Awarded June 25,2022

Certificate in Introduction to Cyber Security, SkillUP by Simplilearn.
 Awarded June 30,2022

## **Technologies and Languages**

Languages: Next JS, Python, HTML, CSS, JS, Flutter, React, React Native, Flask, Dart

Technologies: Git, Firebase, Shade nUI, Radix icons, Firebase, Framer, OpenVsp, Expo, Gradel, Github, Vercel,

Figma

Other: Data structures and algorithms, Davinci Resolve, Adobe Lightroom, Adobe After Effects, Npm,

## **Projects**

 Malici-Chrome Extension - github.com/sylvesterakrong/Malici-Chrome-extension - This project focused on improving safety online by helping to filter urls and sort them into safe or unsafe. I used Html, CSS JS with some basic machine learning principles to develop the extension.

- **Elegant Builders Itd website-** <u>elegantbuildersItd.vercel.app</u> A website that gives the company a good internet presence and puts them on top of their competitors.
- BlogTree blogtree.vercel.app A blog website built with Next JS to allow users express their ideas.

### **Awards**

• Third place award in The Capture the Change: World Earth Day Photography Contest organized by the US Embassy Ghana

(April, 2023)

 High Performance Robot Award, Robofest Online World Championships Finals (August, 2021)

### **Achievements**

- Participated in the Capture the Change: World Earth Day Photography contest organized by the US Embassy Ghana (April, 2023)
- Participated in the World Robotics Olympiad, Germany (Remote), (November 2021)
  - -National Champions(1x) World Finals participant
- Participated in the Robofest Robotics Tournament, Michigan (Remote), (January, 2021)
  - -Qualified from the national stage (January, 2021)
  - -High performance robot award at the world finals (August 2021)
- Participated in Robotics Inspired Science Education(RISE), Accra-Ghana

#### **Interests**

I am interested in UAVs, photography, videography, video and image editing, and occasionally FPS games.